{
  "Digital Electronics": [
    {
      "question": "Which gates are suitable for bit comparison?",
      "correct_answer": "XNOR"
    },
    {
      "question": "The sum expression in half adder is",
      "correct_answer": "X EXORY Y"
    },
    {
      "question": "The difference bit output of a half substractor is same as",
      "correct_answer": "Difference bit of a full substractor"
    },
    {
      "question": "The carry expression in half adder is",
      "correct_answer": "XY"
    },
    {
      "question": "A full adder can be realised by",
      "correct_answer": "Two half adder,one or gates"
    },
    {
      "question": "The number of full adders in a4-bit parallel adder is",
      "correct_answer": "4"
    },
    {
      "question": "The number of full adders required to add 4-bit data in serial adder is",
      "correct_answer": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "MUX is_______implementation",
      "correct_answer": "AND-OR"
    },
    {
      "question": "ROM is________implementation",
      "correct_answer": "Either AND-OR- or AND-OR-NOT"
    },
    {
      "question": "The speed of sequential circuits is_______in comparision with combinational circuits",
      "correct_answer": "Slow"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the is an example for sequential circuit",
      "correct_answer": "Serial adder"
    },
    {
      "question": "Expression for 3-input full adder is,where A,B,C are the inputs",
      "correct_answer": "A XOR B XOR C"
    },
    {
      "question": "Serial adder is designed by using",
      "correct_answer": "A full adder"
    },
    {
      "question": "The characterstic equation of RS-Flipflop",
      "correct_answer": "S+R'Q"
    },
    {
      "question": "What will be the percentage resolution of 5-bit D/A converter",
      "correct_answer": "3.23"
    },
    {
      "question": "In a 6-bit A/D converter the maximum precision supply voltage will be 1.2V. What voltage will 100110 represent",
      "correct_answer": "12.06V"
    },
    {
      "question": "State number of Non Zero states for a 12-bit D/A Converters",
      "correct_answer": "4095"
    },
    {
      "question": "For building a 5-bit simultaneosuly A/D converter,how many Comparators will be required",
      "correct_answer": "32"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following changes the analog voltage to Binary data?",
      "correct_answer": "A/D converter"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which converter has a Binary input?",
      "correct_answer": "D/A converter"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is the fastest A/D converter",
      "correct_answer": "Comparator converter"
    },
    {
      "question": "An A/D converter uses for reference purpose",
      "correct_answer": "A sawtooth wave generator"
    },
    {
      "question": "What will be the percentage resolution of 5-bit D/A converter?",
      "correct_answer": "3.23"
    },
    {
      "question": "In a 6-bit A/D converter the maximum precision supply voltage will be 1.2.V.What voltage will 100110 represent?",
      "correct_answer": "12.06V"
    },
    {
      "question": "State number of Non Zero states for a 12-bit D/A converters",
      "correct_answer": "4095"
    },
    {
      "question": "For building a 5-bit simultaneously A/D converter,how many comparators wil be required",
      "correct_answer": "32"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following changes the analog voltage to binary data",
      "correct_answer": "A/D converter"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which converter has a binary input?",
      "correct_answer": "D/A converter"
    },
    {
      "question": "Expression for 3-input full adder is,where A,B,C are the inputs",
      "correct_answer": "A XOR B XOR C"
    },
    {
      "question": "Serial adder is designed by using",
      "correct_answer": "Full adder and D-flipflop"
    },
    {
      "question": "In a ring counter 1 for N clock pulses the scale for the counter is",
      "correct_answer": "N:1"
    },
    {
      "question": "To get a frequency of 1Hz with an input of 60Hz,we will use",
      "correct_answer": "Divide by 12 counter"
    },
    {
      "question": "If in a shift register Q0 (inverting input) is feedback to input the resulting counter is",
      "correct_answer": "Twisted ring counter with 2N:1 scale"
    },
    {
      "question": "A ring counter is same as",
      "correct_answer": "Shift register"
    },
    {
      "question": "Counter can be used in measurement of",
      "correct_answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following counter results least delay",
      "correct_answer": "Synchronous counter"
    },
    {
      "question": "In a ripple counter using edge triggered J-K Flipflops, The pulse input is applied to?",
      "correct_answer": "Clock input of one flipflops"
    },
    {
      "question": "Shifting a register to left by one bit position is equivalent to?",
      "correct_answer": "Addition of 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "In a shift register, the stage which is to star MSB is converted into",
      "correct_answer": "D type latch"
    },
    {
      "question": "In a digital counter the number of flipflops is",
      "correct_answer": "None"
    }
  ],
  "Micro Processors": [
    {
      "question": "CPU Stands for",
      "correct_answer": "Central processing unit"
    },
    {
      "question": "ALU stands for",
      "correct_answer": "Arithmetic logic unit"
    },
    {
      "question": "A programmable device similar to CPU",
      "correct_answer": "Microprocessor"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a 16-bit microprocessor",
      "correct_answer": "8086"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following microprocessor has 16 data lines",
      "correct_answer": "8086"
    },
    {
      "question": "8085 microprocessor has___________address lines",
      "correct_answer": "16"
    },
    {
      "question": "8085 microprocessor has data lines",
      "correct_answer": "8"
    },
    {
      "question": "Maximum memory which can be connected with 8085 microprocessor is",
      "correct_answer": "64KB"
    },
    {
      "question": "Program counter (PC)/Instruction pointer (IP) is used to",
      "correct_answer": "Point the address of next instruction to be executed"
    },
    {
      "question": "Stack pointer (SP) is a________bit register",
      "correct_answer": "16"
    },
    {
      "question": "8086 microprocessor has________pins",
      "correct_answer": "40"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is an interrupt pin of 8086 microprocessor",
      "correct_answer": "NMI"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is an interrupt pin of 8086 microprocessor",
      "correct_answer": "TRAP"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which flag is affected by data transfer instruction",
      "correct_answer": "No"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not an I/O interfacing technique",
      "correct_answer": "Memorymapped I/O"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following instruction is correct",
      "correct_answer": "IN FF"
    },
    {
      "question": "IN instruction requires___________T-states",
      "correct_answer": "10"
    },
    {
      "question": "OUT instruction requires__________T-states",
      "correct_answer": "10"
    },
    {
      "question": "CALL instruction requires_________T-states",
      "correct_answer": "18"
    },
    {
      "question": "Microprocessor find applications in",
      "correct_answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "In Von-Neumann or Princeton type computer,the program",
      "correct_answer": "Can appear anywhere within the memory"
    },
    {
      "question": "The instruction cycle is made up of",
      "correct_answer": "One or more fetch cycle"
    },
    {
      "question": "The maximum integer which can be stored on an 8-bit accumulator",
      "correct_answer": "255"
    },
    {
      "question": "The______built on a single LSI/ULSI chip os called microprocessor",
      "correct_answer": "CPU"
    },
    {
      "question": "The 8085 has_______interrupt pins",
      "correct_answer": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "The instruction MOV AX,0016H is an example of addressing mode",
      "correct_answer": "Immediate"
    },
    {
      "question": "The instruction MOV AX,[200H] is an example of-addressing mode",
      "correct_answer": "I/O port"
    },
    {
      "question": "The instruction IN AL, 19H is an example of_______addressing mode",
      "correct_answer": "I/O port"
    },
    {
      "question": "The instruction CMC is an example of________addressing mode",
      "correct_answer": "Implicit"
    },
    {
      "question": "In minimum mode of operation of 8086,________number of processors is used",
      "correct_answer": "1"
    }
  ],
  "Operating Systems": [
    {
      "question": "Which of the following scheduling algorithm gives minimum average waiting time?",
      "correct_answer": "SJF"
    },
    {
      "question": "Page fault occurs when?",
      "correct_answer": "The page is not in main memory"
    },
    {
      "question": "Determine the no. of page faults when references to pages occur in the following order 12452124 assume that the main memory can accommodate 3pages and the main memory already has the pages 1&2 with page 1 having brought earlier than page2(LRU algorithm is used).",
      "correct_answer": "4"
    },
    {
      "question": "Necessary conditions for deadlock are",
      "correct_answer": "Both A&B"
    },
    {
      "question": "At a particular time of computation the value of counting semaphore is 7.then 20 p operations and '\u00d7' v operations were completed on this semaphore. If the final value of the semaphore is 5,x will be",
      "correct_answer": "18"
    },
    {
      "question": "The structure that allows you to choose graphical symbols (or) pictures instead of typing\ncommand to do work on our PC is called a",
      "correct_answer": "Symbolic screen"
    },
    {
      "question": "To get the task manager window in Windows 95",
      "correct_answer": "Press ALT-CTRL-DEL"
    },
    {
      "question": "Statements is one are true",
      "correct_answer": "Only ii & iv"
    },
    {
      "question": "PCB is an abbreviation for process control block. The following five statements are related to PCB. Which of these is one are true?",
      "correct_answer": "PCB is a Data Structure"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is one are true about a process?",
      "correct_answer": "A process is a program execution"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following statements is one are true with regard to threads?",
      "correct_answer": "Multi threads use the same address space and share it between threads"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a true statement about a deadlock?",
      "correct_answer": "None of the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is one are the correct statements with regard to page replacement and page replacing algorithms",
      "correct_answer": "All the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "Memory access by its contents is known as",
      "correct_answer": "Associative memory"
    },
    {
      "question": "The operating system controls",
      "correct_answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "Suppose a system has equivalents tape drives three concurrent process p1, p2 & p3 require three , two and four of these tape drives respectively. To complete their execution. At a given instance two and one of the these process p1, p2 & p3 respectively. 17. In a paged memory system let Which of the following allocations will bring the system to an unsafe state?",
      "correct_answer": "Allocation two tape drives to process \u04403"
    },
    {
      "question": "In a paged memory system let w-0,4,1,4, 1,5,1,6,2,6,3,6, 2,6,4,5 be a page reference stream. Assuming that the main memory can have only 3 pages frames and all the page frames are initially empty, new many page faults will the given reference stream incur if the FIFO replacement strategy is used?",
      "correct_answer": "9"
    },
    {
      "question": "Critical region is",
      "correct_answer": "A set of instructions that access common shared resources which exclude one another in time"
    },
    {
      "question": "Djakarta's banking algorithm in an Os solves the problem of",
      "correct_answer": "Deadlock avoidance"
    },
    {
      "question": "Direct access methods are not effectively supported by",
      "correct_answer": "Linked allocation"
    },
    {
      "question": "Attach (or) Detach remote devices is the following type of system call",
      "correct_answer": "Device management"
    },
    {
      "question": "Mail box provides",
      "correct_answer": "A OR B"
    },
    {
      "question": "Disadvantage of the fixed partitioning of memory is",
      "correct_answer": "Internal fragmentation"
    },
    {
      "question": "Select the method which is not used for free space management",
      "correct_answer": "Inverted List"
    },
    {
      "question": "The following disk scheduling algorithm perform better for systems that place heavy\n          load on the disk",
      "correct_answer": "C-SCAN"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following page replacement algorithms exhibits belady's anomaly?",
      "correct_answer": "FIFO"
    },
    {
      "question": "To avoid race condition the no.of processes that can be allowed to be simultaneously inside the critical\n          section is",
      "correct_answer": "2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is meant by a process?",
      "correct_answer": "A program written in high level language & stored on the disk"
    },
    {
      "question": "A computer system cannot boot if the______is not available on it",
      "correct_answer": "Loader"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the use of job control language (JCL) statements?",
      "correct_answer": "Inform the OS, the start and end of a job in a match"
    },
    {
      "question": "Attach (or) Detach remote devices is the following type of system call",
      "correct_answer": "Device management"
    },
    {
      "question": "Mail box provides",
      "correct_answer": "A OR B"
    },
    {
      "question": "Disadvantage of the fixed partitioning of memory is",
      "correct_answer": "Internal fragmentation"
    },
    {
      "question": "Select the method which is not used for free space management",
      "correct_answer": "Inverted List"
    },
    {
      "question": "The following disk scheduling algorithm perform better for systems that place heavy\nload on the disk",
      "correct_answer": "C-SCAN"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following page replacement algorithms exhibits belady's anomaly?",
      "correct_answer": "FIFO"
    },
    {
      "question": "To avoid race condition the no.of processes that can be allowed to be simultaneously inside the critical section is",
      "correct_answer": "2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is meant by a process?",
      "correct_answer": "A program written in high level language & stored on the disk"
    },
    {
      "question": "A computer system cannot boot if the______is not available on it",
      "correct_answer": "Loader"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the use of job control language (JCL) statements?",
      "correct_answer": "Inform the OS, the start and end of a job in a match"
    }
  ],
  "C Programming": [
    {
      "question": "In which header file is the NULL macro defined?",
      "correct_answer": "stdio.h and stddef.h"
    },
    {
      "question": "How many bytes are occupied by near, far and huge pointers (DOS)?",
      "correct_answer": "near=2 far=4 huge=4"
    },
    {
      "question": "If a variable is a pointer to a structure, then which of the following operator is used to access data members of the structure through the pointer variable?",
      "correct_answer": "->"
    },
    {
      "question": "What would be the equivalent pointer expression for referring the array element?\na) [i]U][k]U]",
      "correct_answer": "*(*(*(*(a+i)+j)+k)+|)"
    },
    {
      "question": "A pointer is?",
      "correct_answer": "A variable that stores address of other variable"
    },
    {
      "question": "The operator used to get value at address stored in a pointer variable is",
      "correct_answer": "*"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following function sets first n characters of a string to a given character?",
      "correct_answer": "strnset) y"
    },
    {
      "question": "If the two strings are identical, then strcmp() function returns",
      "correct_answer": "0"
    },
    {
      "question": "How will you print \\n on the screen?",
      "correct_answer": "printf(\"\\\\n\");"
    },
    {
      "question": "The library function used to find the last Occurrence of a character in a string is",
      "correct_answer": "strrchr()"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following statements should be used to obtain a remainder after dividing 3.14 by 2.1?",
      "correct_answer": "rem = fmod(3.14, 2.1);"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the types of linkages?",
      "correct_answer": "External, Internal and None"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following special symbol allowed in a variable name?",
      "correct_answer": "_ (underscore)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Is there any difference between following declarations?\n1: extern int fun();\n2: int fun();",
      "correct_answer": "No difference, except extern int fun(); is probably in another file"
    },
    {
      "question": "How would you round off a value from 1.66 to 2.0?",
      "correct_answer": "ceil(1.66)"
    },
    {
      "question": "By default a real number is treated as a?",
      "correct_answer": "Double"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not user defined data type?\n1:\n  struct book\n  {\n  char name [10];\n  float price;\n  int pages;\n  };\n2: long int I = 2.35;\n3: enum day {Sun, Mon, Tue, Wed);",
      "correct_answer": "2"
    },
    {
      "question": "Is the following statement a declaration or definition?\n(extern int i;)",
      "correct_answer": "Declaration"
    },
    {
      "question": "Identify which of the following are declarations?\n1: extern int x;\n2: float square ( float x ) { ... }\n3: double pow(double, double);",
      "correct_answer": "1 and 3 *"
    },
    {
      "question": "In the following program where is the variable a getting defined and where it is getting declared?\n#includeint main ()\n{\nextern int a;\nprinf(\"%d\\n\", a);\nreturn 0;\n}\nint a=20;",
      "correct_answer": "extern int a is declaration, int a = 20 is the definition"
    },
    {
      "question": "Where we mention the prototype of a function?",
      "correct_answer": "Declaring"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following correctly shows the hierarchy of arithmetic operations in C?",
      "correct_answer": "/ * + -"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is the correct order if calling functions in the below code?\na = f1(23, 14) * f2(12/4) + f3();",
      "correct_answer": "Order may vary from compiler to compiler"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is the correct usage of conditional operators used in C?",
      "correct_answer": "max =a>b ? a>c?a:c:b>c?b:c"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following are unary operators in C?\n1.!\n2.sizeof\n3.~\n4.&&",
      "correct_answer": "1, 2, 3"
    },
    {
      "question": "In which order do the following gets evaluated?\n1. Relational\n2.Arithmetic\n3.Logical\n4.Assignment",
      "correct_answer": "2134"
    },
    {
      "question": "The keyword used to transfer control from a function back to the calling function is?",
      "correct_answer": "return"
    },
    {
      "question": "How many times the program will print \"krishna\" ?\n#includeint main ()\n{\nprintff\"krishna\");\nmain();\nreturn 0;",
      "correct_answer": "Till stack overflows"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is (void*)0?",
      "correct_answer": "Representation of NULL pointer"
    },
    {
      "question": "Can you combine the following two statements into one?\nchar *p;\np = (char*) malloc (100);",
      "correct_answer": "char *p = (char*) malloc(100);"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following function is used to find the first occurrence of a given string in another string?",
      "correct_answer": "strstr()"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following function is more appropriate for reading in a multi-word string?",
      "correct_answer": "gets();"
    },
    {
      "question": "What will the function rewind() do?",
      "correct_answer": "Reposition the file pointer to begining of file"
    },
    {
      "question": "Input/output function prototypes and macros are defined in which header file?",
      "correct_answer": "stdio.h"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which standard library function will you use to find the last occurance of a character in a string in C?",
      "correct_answer": "strrchr()"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is stderr?",
      "correct_answer": "Standard error streams"
    },
    {
      "question": "Does there any function exist to convert the int or float to a string?",
      "correct_answer": "Yes"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of fflush() function.",
      "correct_answer": "Flushes all streams and specified streams"
    },
    {
      "question": "Can you use the fprintf() to display the output on the screen?",
      "correct_answer": "Yes"
    },
    {
      "question": "What will the function randomize() do in Turbo C under DOS?",
      "correct_answer": "Returns a random number generator with a random value based on time"
    }
  ],
  "Data Structures": [
    {
      "question": "Which if the following is/are the levels of implementation of data structure",
      "correct_answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "A binary search tree whose left subtree and right subtree differ in Hight by at most 1 unit is called ......",
      "correct_answer": "AVL tree"
    },
    {
      "question": "___________ level is where the model becomes compatible executable code",
      "correct_answer": "Implementation level"
    },
    {
      "question": "Stack is also called as",
      "correct_answer": "Last in first out"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is true about the characteristics of abstract data types?\ni) It exports a type.\nii) It exports a set of operations",
      "correct_answer": "True, True"
    },
    {
      "question": "___________ is not the component of data structure.",
      "correct_answer": "None of above"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not the part of ADT description?",
      "correct_answer": "None of the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "Inserting an item into the stack when stack is not full is called _________ Operation and deletion of item form the stack, when stack is not empty is called  _______ operation.",
      "correct_answer": "push, pop"
    },
    {
      "question": "___________ Is a pile in which items are added at one end and removed from the other.",
      "correct_answer": "Queue"
    },
    {
      "question": "___________ is very useful in situation when data have to stored and then retrieved in reverse order.",
      "correct_answer": "Queue"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which data structure allows deleting data elements from and inserting at rear?",
      "correct_answer": "Queues"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following data structure can't store the non-homogeneous data elements?",
      "correct_answer": "Arrays"
    },
    {
      "question": "A  ___________is a data structure that organizes data similar to a line in the supermarket, where the first one in line is the first one out.",
      "correct_answer": "Queue linked list"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is non-liner data structure?",
      "correct_answer": "Trees"
    },
    {
      "question": "Herder node is used as sentinel in  ___________",
      "correct_answer": "Binary tree"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which data structure is used in breadth first search of a graph to hold nodes?",
      "correct_answer": "queue"
    },
    {
      "question": "Identify the data structure which allows deletions at both ends of the list but insertion at only one end.",
      "correct_answer": "Input restricted dequeue"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following data structure is non linear type?",
      "correct_answer": "Graph"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which cf the following data structure is linear type?",
      "correct_answer": "Stack"
    },
    {
      "question": "To represent hierarchical relationship between elements, Which data structure is suitable?",
      "correct_answer": "Tree"
    },
    {
      "question": "A directed graph is every on. If there is, path from each vertex to every other vertex in the digraph.",
      "correct_answer": "Strongly Connected"
    },
    {
      "question": "In the ___________ traversal we process all of a vertex's descendants before we move to an adjacent vertex.",
      "correct_answer": "Depth First"
    },
    {
      "question": "State True of False.\ni) Network is a graph that has weights or costs associated with it.\nii) An undirected graph which contains no cycles is called a forest.\nill) A graph is said to be complete if there is no edge between every pair of vertices.",
      "correct_answer": "True, True, False"
    },
    {
      "question": "Match the following.\na) Completeness i) How long does it take to find a solution\nb) Time Complexity i) How much memory need to perform the search.\nc) Space Complexity ill) Is the strategy guaranteed to find the solution when there in\none.",
      "correct_answer": "a-iii, b-i, c-ii"
    },
    {
      "question": "The number of comparisons done by sequential search is ___________",
      "correct_answer": "(N+1)/2"
    },
    {
      "question": "In ______ search start at the beginning of he list and check every element in the list.",
      "correct_answer": "Linear search"
    },
    {
      "question": "State True or False. \ni)Binary search is used for searching in a sorted array.\ni)The time complexity of binary search is O(logn).",
      "correct_answer": "True, True"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not the internal sort?",
      "correct_answer": "Merge Sort"
    },
    {
      "question": "State True or False.\ni)An undirected graph which contains no cycles is called forest.\nii) A graph is said to be complete if there is an edge between every pair of vertices.",
      "correct_answer": "True, True"
    },
    {
      "question": "A graph is said to be ___________ it the vertices can be split into two sets V1 and V2 such there are no edges between two vertices of V1 or two vertices of V2.",
      "correct_answer": "Bipartite"
    },
    {
      "question": "In a queue, the initial values of front pointer f rare pointer r should be ............. and ......... respectively.",
      "correct_answer": "0 and -1"
    },
    {
      "question": "In a circular queue the value of r will be ___________",
      "correct_answer": "r= (r+1)% QUEUE_SIZE"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following statement is true?\ni) Using singly linked lists and circular list, it is not possible to traverse the list backwards. \nii) To find the predecessor, it is required to traverse the list from the first node in case of singly linked list.",
      "correct_answer": "Both i and ii"
    },
    {
      "question": "The advantage of ............ is that they solve the problem if sequential storage representation. But disadvantage in that is they are sequential lists.",
      "correct_answer": "Linked Lists"
    },
    {
      "question": "What will be the value of top, if there is a size of stack STACK_SIZE is 5",
      "correct_answer": "4"
    },
    {
      "question": "........ is not the operation that can be performed on queue.",
      "correct_answer": "Traversal"
    },
    {
      "question": "There is an extra element at the head of the list called a ......",
      "correct_answer": "Sentinel"
    },
    {
      "question": "A graph is a collection of nodes, called .......... And line segments called arcs or .............. that connect pair of nodes.",
      "correct_answer": "vertices, edges"
    },
    {
      "question": "A ....... is a graph that has weights of costs associated with its edges.",
      "correct_answer": "Both A and B"
    },
    {
      "question": "In general, the binary search method needs no more than ___________ comparisons.",
      "correct_answer": "[log2n]+1"
    }
  ],
  "Computer Networks": [
    {
      "question": "Computer Network is",
      "correct_answer": "All of the Above"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a Firewall in Computer Network?",
      "correct_answer": "A system designed to prevent unauthorized access"
    },
    {
      "question": "How many layers does OSI Reference Model has?",
      "correct_answer": "7"
    },
    {
      "question": "DHCP is the abbreviation of",
      "correct_answer": "Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol"
    },
    {
      "question": "IPV4 Address is",
      "correct_answer": "32 bit"
    },
    {
      "question": "DNS is the abbreviation of",
      "correct_answer": "Domain Name System"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the meaning of Bandwidth in Network?",
      "correct_answer": "Transmission capacity of a communication channels"
    },
    {
      "question": "ADSL is the abbreviation of",
      "correct_answer": "Asymmetric Digital Subscriber Line"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the use of Bridge in Network?",
      "correct_answer": "to connect LANs"
    },
    {
      "question": "Router operates in which layer of OSl Reference Model?",
      "correct_answer": "Layer 3 (Network Layer)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Each IP packet must contain",
      "correct_answer": "Source and Destination address"
    },
    {
      "question": "Bridge works in which layer of the OSI model?",
      "correct_answer": "Datalink layer"
    },
    {
      "question": "_____________ provides a connection-oriented reliable service for sending messages",
      "correct_answer": "TCP"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which layers of the OS model are host-to-host layers?",
      "correct_answer": "Transport, Session, Presentation, Application"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following IP address class is Multicast",
      "correct_answer": "Class D"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is correct regarding Class B Address of IP address",
      "correct_answer": "Network bit - 14, Host bit - 16"
    },
    {
      "question": "The last address of IP address represents",
      "correct_answer": "Broadcast address"
    },
    {
      "question": "How many bits are there in the Ethernet address?",
      "correct_answer": "48 bits"
    },
    {
      "question": "How many layers are in the TCP/IP model?",
      "correct_answer": "4 layers"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following laver of OSI model also called end-to-end layer?",
      "correct_answer": "Transport laver"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why IP Protocol is considered as unreliable?",
      "correct_answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "All of the above",
      "correct_answer": "20 bytes"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of following provides reliable communication?",
      "correct_answer": "TCP"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the address size of IPv6 ?",
      "correct_answer": "128 bit"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the size of Network bits & Host bits of Class A of IP address?",
      "correct_answer": "Network bits 7, Host bits 24"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does Router do in a network?",
      "correct_answer": "Determines on which outing link a packet is to be forwarded"
    },
    {
      "question": "The Internet is an example of",
      "correct_answer": "Packet switched network"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does protocol defines?",
      "correct_answer": "All of above"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the uses of subnetting?",
      "correct_answer": "It divides one large network into several smaller ones"
    },
    {
      "question": "Repeater operates in which layer of the OSI model?",
      "correct_answer": "Physical layer"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the benefit of the Networking?",
      "correct_answer": "All of the Above"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not the Networking Devices?",
      "correct_answer": "Linux"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the size of MAC Address?",
      "correct_answer": "48-bits"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following can be Software?",
      "correct_answer": "Firewalls"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the use of Ping command?",
      "correct_answer": "To test a device on the network is reachable"
    },
    {
      "question": "MAC Address is the example of",
      "correct_answer": "Data Link Layer"
    },
    {
      "question": "Routing tables of a router keeps track of",
      "correct_answer": "Routes to use for forwarding data to its destination"
    },
    {
      "question": "Layer-2 Switch is also called",
      "correct_answer": "Multiport Bridge"
    },
    {
      "question": "Difference between T568A and T568B is",
      "correct_answer": "Just different manufacturer standards"
    },
    {
      "question": "The meaning of Straight-through Cable is",
      "correct_answer": "Four wire pairs connect to the same pin on each end"
    }
  ],
  "Rdbms(DBMS)": [
    {
      "question": "If the closure of an attribute set is the entire relation then the attribute set is a",
      "correct_answer": "Superkey"
    },
    {
      "question": "DROP is a ________________ statement in SQL",
      "correct_answer": "DDL"
    },
    {
      "question": "If two relations R and S are joined, then the non matching tuples of both R and S are ignored in",
      "correct_answer": "Inner join"
    },
    {
      "question": "The keyword to eliminate duplicate rows from the query result in SQL is",
      "correct_answer": "UNIQUE"
    },
    {
      "question": "In 2NF",
      "correct_answer": "No partial FDs exist"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which one is correct statement?\nLogical data independence provides following without changing application programs:\n(i) Changes in access methods.\n(ii) Adding new entities in database\n(iii) Splitting an existing record into two or more records\n(iv) Changing storage medium",
      "correct_answer": "(ii) and (iii)"
    },
    {
      "question": "In an E-R, Y is the dominant entity and X is a subordinate entity. Then which of the following is incorrect:",
      "correct_answer": "Operationally, if X is deleted, so is Y"
    },
    {
      "question": "Relational Algebra is",
      "correct_answer": "Procedural query Language"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following aggregate functions does not ignore nulls in its results?",
      "correct_answer": "COUNT (*)"
    },
    {
      "question": "R (A, B,C, D) is a relation. Which of the following does not have a lossless join dependency preserving BCNF decomposition",
      "correct_answer": "A_BCD"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following relational algebra operations do not require the participating tables to be union-compatible?",
      "correct_answer": "Join"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not a property of transactions?",
      "correct_answer": "Concurrency"
    },
    {
      "question": "Relational Algebra does not have",
      "correct_answer": "Aggregation operators"
    },
    {
      "question": "Checkpoints are a part of",
      "correct_answer": "Recovery measures"
    },
    {
      "question": "Tree structures are used to store data in",
      "correct_answer": "Hierarchical model"
    },
    {
      "question": "The language that requires a user to specify the data to be retrieved without specifying exactly how to get it is",
      "correct_answer": "Non-Procedural DML"
    },
    {
      "question": "Precedence graphs help to find a AC14/AT11 Database Management Systems2",
      "correct_answer": "Serializable schedule"
    },
    {
      "question": "The rule that a value of a foreign key must appear as a value of some specitic table is called a?",
      "correct_answer": "Referential constraint"
    },
    {
      "question": "The clause in SQL that specifies that the query result should be sorted in ascending or descending order based on the values of one or more columns is?",
      "correct_answer": "Order by"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a disjoint less constraint?",
      "correct_answer": "It requires that an entity belongs to no more than one level entity set"
    },
    {
      "question": "According to the levels of abstraction, the schema at the intermediate level is called",
      "correct_answer": "Logical schema"
    },
    {
      "question": "It is an abstraction through which relationships are treated as higher level entities",
      "correct_answer": "Specialization"
    },
    {
      "question": "A relation is in _____________ if an attribute of a composite key is dependent on an attribute of other composite key",
      "correct_answer": "3NF"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is data integrity?",
      "correct_answer": "It is the data contained in database that is accurate and consistent"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the desirable properties of a decomposition",
      "correct_answer": "Dependency preservation"
    },
    {
      "question": "In an E-R diagram double lines indicate",
      "correct_answer": "Total participation"
    },
    {
      "question": "The operation which is not considered a basic operation of relational algebra is?",
      "correct_answer": "Join"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fifth Normal form is concerned with",
      "correct_answer": "Join dependency"
    },
    {
      "question": "Block-interleaved distributed parity is RAID level",
      "correct_answer": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "Immediate database modification technique uses",
      "correct_answer": "Both undo and redo"
    },
    {
      "question": "In SQL the statement select * from R, S is equivalent to",
      "correct_answer": "Select * from R cross join S"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not a consequence of concurrent operations?",
      "correct_answer": "Update anomaly"
    },
    {
      "question": "As per equivalence rules for query transformation, selection operation distributes over",
      "correct_answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "The metadata is created by the",
      "correct_answer": "DDL interpreter"
    },
    {
      "question": "When an E-R diagram is mapped to tables, the representation is redundant for",
      "correct_answer": "Weak relationship sets"
    },
    {
      "question": "When R[?] S[?][?][?][?]; then the cost of computing R >< S is",
      "correct_answer": "The same as R [?][?]"
    },
    {
      "question": "In SQL the word 'natural can be used with",
      "correct_answer": "Inner join"
    },
    {
      "question": "The default level of consistency in SQL is",
      "correct_answer": "Serializable"
    },
    {
      "question": "If a transaction T has obtained an exclusive lock on item Q, then T can",
      "correct_answer": "Both read and write Q"
    },
    {
      "question": "Shadow paging has",
      "correct_answer": "No redo"
    }
  ],
  "Oops Through C++": [
    {
      "question": "Who invented OOP?",
      "correct_answer": "Alan Kay"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is not feature of OOP in general definitions?",
      "correct_answer": "Duplicate/Redundant data"
    },
    {
      "question": "Pure OOP can be implemented without using class in a program",
      "correct_answer": "False"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Feature of OOP illustrated the code reusability?",
      "correct_answer": "Polymorphism"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not type of class?",
      "correct_answer": "Start Class"
    },
    {
      "question": "Class is pass by ____________",
      "correct_answer": "Reference"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is default access specifier for data members or member functions declared within a class without any specifier, in C++?",
      "correct_answer": "Private"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is most appropriate comment on following class definition:\nclass Student\n{\nint a;\npublic: float a;\n};",
      "correct_answer": "Error: same variable name can't be used twice"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is known as generic class?",
      "correct_answer": "Template class"
    },
    {
      "question": "Size of a class is :",
      "correct_answer": "Classes doesn't have any size"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which class can have member functions without their implementation?",
      "correct_answer": "Abstract class"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following describes a friend class?",
      "correct_answer": "Friend class can access all the private members of the class, of which it is a friend"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is scope of a class nested inside another class?",
      "correct_answer": "Protected scope"
    },
    {
      "question": "Class with main() function can be inherited (True/False)",
      "correct_answer": "True"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which among the following is faise, for member function of a class?",
      "correct_answer": "Member functions need not be declared inside the class definition"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which syntax for class definition is wrong?",
      "correct_answer": "Class student{ };"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following pairs are similar?",
      "correct_answer": "Class and structure"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which among the following is false for class features?",
      "correct_answer": "Class definition must be ended with a colon"
    },
    {
      "question": "Instance of which type of class can't be created?",
      "correct_answer": "Abstract class"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which definition best describes an object?",
      "correct_answer": "Instance of a class"
    },
    {
      "question": "How many objects can be declared of a specific class in a single program?",
      "correct_answer": "As many as you want"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which among the following is false?",
      "correct_answer": "Objects can't be passed by reference"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is incorrect?",
      "correct_answer": "Class student{ }s[];"
    },
    {
      "question": "The object can't be:",
      "correct_answer": "Passed as function"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is size of the object of following class (64 bit system)?\nclass student {int rollno; char name[20];\nstatic int studentno; };",
      "correct_answer": "24"
    },
    {
      "question": "Functions can't return objects (True/False)",
      "correct_answer": "False"
    },
    {
      "question": "How members of an object are accessed?",
      "correct_answer": "Using dot operator/period symbol"
    },
    {
      "question": "If a local class is defined in a function, which of the following is true for an object of that class?",
      "correct_answer": "Object can be used/accessed/declared locally in that function"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which among the following is wrong?",
      "correct_answer": "Abstract class student{ }; student s;"
    },
    {
      "question": "Object declared in main() function:",
      "correct_answer": "Can't be used by any other function"
    },
    {
      "question": "When an object is returned ______________",
      "correct_answer": "A temporary object is created to return the value"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which among the following is correct?",
      "correct_answer": "class student{ }s1,s2; s1=s2;"
    },
    {
      "question": "How many classes can be defined in a single program?",
      "correct_answer": "As many as you want"
    },
    {
      "question": "When OOP concept did first came into picture?",
      "correct_answer": "1970's"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which rule will not affect the friend function?",
      "correct_answer": "Private and protected members of a class cannot be accessed from outside"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the syntax of friend function?",
      "correct_answer": "Friend class1 Class2;"
    },
    {
      "question": "Pick out the correct statement",
      "correct_answer": "A friend function may or may not be a member of another class"
    },
    {
      "question": "Where does keyword 'friend' should be placed?",
      "correct_answer": "Function declaration"
    },
    {
      "question": "Where is the derived class is derived from?",
      "correct_answer": "Base"
    },
    {
      "question": "Pick out the correct statement",
      "correct_answer": "A derived class's distructor cannot involve its base class's distructor"
    }
  ],
  "Java Programming": [
    {
      "question": "Which four options describe the correct default values for array elements of the types indicated?                                                                                                                                  1. int -> O\n2. String -> \"null\"\n3. Dog -> null\n4. char -> '\\u0000'\n5. float -> 0.0f\n6. boolean -> true",
      "correct_answer": "1, 3, 4, 5"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which one of these lists contains only Java programming language keywords?",
      "correct_answer": "goto, instanceof, native, finally, default, throws"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which will legally declare, construct, and initialize an array?",
      "correct_answer": "int myList [] = {4, 3, 7};"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is a reserved word in the Java programming language?",
      "correct_answer": "Native"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is a valid keyword in java?",
      "correct_answer": "Interface"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which three are legal array declarations?                                                                                       1. int [] myScores [];\n2. char [] myChars;\n3. int [6] myScores;\n4. Dog myDogs [];\n5. Dog myDogs [7];",
      "correct_answer": "1, 2, 4"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is the valid declarations within an interface definition?",
      "correct_answer": "public double methoda();"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is a valid declarations of a String?",
      "correct_answer": "String s1 = null;"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the numerical range of a char?",
      "correct_answer": "O to 65535"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which three are valid declarations of a float?                                                                                     1. float f1 = -343;\n2. float f2 = 3.14;\n3. float f3 = 0x12345;\n4. float f4 = 42e7;\n5. float f5 = 2001.0D;\n6. float f6 = 2.81F;",
      "correct_answer": "1, 3, 6"
    },
    {
      "question": "Public interface Foo                                                                                                                                   {\nint k = 4; /* Line 3 */\n}\nWhich three piece of codes are equivalent to line 3?\n1. final int k = 4;\n2. public int k = 4;\n3. static int k = 4;\n4. abstract int k = 4;\n5. volatile int k = 4;\n6. protected int k = 4;",
      "correct_answer": "1, 2 and 3"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which one of the following will declare an array and initialize it with five numbers?",
      "correct_answer": "int [] a = {23,22,21,20,19};"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the value of \"d\" after this line of code has been executed?                                           double d = Math.round ( 2.5 + Math.random() );",
      "correct_answer": "3"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following would compile without error?",
      "correct_answer": "int a = Math.abs(-5);"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following are valid calls to Math.max?                                                                      1. Math.max(1,4)\n2. Math.ma\u00d7(2.3, 5)\n3. Math.max(1, 3, 5, 7)\n4. Math.max(-1.5, -2.8f)",
      "correct_answer": "1, 2 and 4"
    },
    {
      "question": "What allows the programmer to destroy an object x?",
      "correct_answer": "Only the garbage collection system can destroy an object"
    },
    {
      "question": "You want subclasses in any package to have access to members of a superclass. Which is the most restrictive access that accomplishes this obiective?",
      "correct_answer": "Protected"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which three form part of correct array declarations?                                                                                                           1. public int a []\n2. static int [] a\n3. public [] int a\n4. private int a [3]\n5. private int [3] a [ ]\n6. public final int [] a",
      "correct_answer": "1, 2, 6"
    },
    {
      "question": "public class Test\n{\n}\nWhat is the prototype of the default\nconstructor?",
      "correct_answer": "public Test()"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the most restrictive access modifier that will allow members of one class to have access to members of another class in the same package?",
      "correct_answer": "Default access"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is/are legal method declarations?\n1. protected abstract void m1();\n2. static final void m1(){}\n3. synchronized public final void m1() {}\n4. private native void m1();",
      "correct_answer": "All of them are legal declarations"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which three are valid method signatures in an interface?\n1. private int getArea();\n2. public float getVol (float x);\n3. public void main (String [] args);\n4. pubic statice void main (String [] args);\n5. boolean setFlag (Boolean [] test);",
      "correct_answer": "2, 3 and 5"
    },
    {
      "question": "You want a class to have access to members of another class in the same package. Which is the most restrictive access that accomplishes this objective?",
      "correct_answer": "Private"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which one creates an instance of an array?",
      "correct_answer": "int[] ia = new int[15];"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which two of the following are legal declarations for non-nested classes and interfaces?\n1. final abstract class Test {}\n2. public static interface Test {}\n3. final public class Test {}\n4. protected abstract class Test {}\n5. protected interface Test {]\n6. abstract public class Test {}",
      "correct_answer": "3 and 6"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following class level (non-local) variable declarations will not compile?",
      "correct_answer": "private synchronized int e;"
    },
    {
      "question": "Given a method in a protected class, what access modifier do vou use to restrict access to that method to only the other members of the same class?",
      "correct_answer": "Private"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is a valid declaration within an interface?",
      "correct_answer": "public static short stop = 23;"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which two statements are true for any concrete class implementing the java. lang. Runnable interface?\n1. You can extend the Runnable interface as long as you override the public run() method.\n2. The class must contain a method cailed run() from which all code for that thread will be initiated.\n3. The class must contain an empty public void method named run().\n4. The class must contain a public void method named runnable ().\n5. The class definition must include the words implements Threads and contain a method called run().\n6. The mandatory method must be public, with a return type of void, must be called run(), and cannot take any arguments.",
      "correct_answer": "2 and 6"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which three statements are true?\n1. The default constructor initialises method variables.\n2. The default constructor has the same access as its class.\n3. The default constructor invokes the no-arg constructor of the superclass.\n4. If a class lacks a no-ars constructor, the compiler always creates a default constructor.\n5. The compiler creates a default constructor only when there are no other constructors for the class.",
      "correct_answer": "2, 3 and 5"
    },
    {
      "question": "Suppose that you would like to create an instance of a new Map that has an iteration order that is the same as the iteration order of an existing instance of a Map. Which concrete implementation of the Map interface should be used for the new instance?",
      "correct_answer": "LinkedHashMap"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which class does not override the equals() and hashCode() methods, inheriting them directly from class Object?",
      "correct_answer": "java.lang.String Buffer"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which collection class allows you to grow or shrink its size and provides indexed access to its elements, but whose methods are not synchronized?",
      "correct_answer": "java.util.ArrayList"
    },
    {
      "question": "You need to store elements in a collection that guarantees that no duplicates are stored and all elements can be accessed in natural order. Which interface provides that capability?",
      "correct_answer": "java.util.Set"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which interface does java.util. Hashtable implement?",
      "correct_answer": "Java. util. Map"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which interface provides the capability to store objects using a key-value pair?",
      "correct_answer": "Java.util. Map"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which collection class allows you to associate its elements with key values, and allows you to retrieve objects in FIFO (first-in, first-out) sequence?",
      "correct_answer": "java.util. LinkedHashMap"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which collection class allows you to access its elements by associating a key with an element's value, and provides synchronization?",
      "correct_answer": "java.util. Hashtable"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is valid declaration of a float?",
      "correct_answer": "float f = 1F;"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following are Java reserved Words?\n1:run,2:import,3:import,4:implement",
      "correct_answer": "2 and 3"
    }
  ]
}